German Democratic Republic Subject Files, Inclusive: 1951-2007, undated, Bulk: 1977-1990
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
German Democratic Republic Subject Files
Inclusive: 1951-2007, undated, Bulk: 1977-1990
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/
6
Keston Institute, 1969 -
28 A4 document boxes
The German Democratic Republic Subject Files contain a variety of materials on religious persecution, state religious policies, communist ideology, political leaders, religious publications, and international affairs pertaining to the country.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Keston College, originally founded in 1969 as the Center for the Study of Religion and Communism with the named changed to Keston College in 1974, collected and publicized details about religious persecution behind the Iron Curtain, becoming “the voice of the voiceless.” After the collapse of communism in the 1990s, Keston College moved to Oxford and downsized due to decreased funding. The name eventually changed to Keston Institute. In 2007, the Institute transferred the Keston Archive and Library to the newly created Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society at Baylor University.
Keston collected, verified, translated, and disseminated information received from believers in the Soviet Union, Poland, Romania, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, Bulgaria and other communist countries. The Keston Archive and Library housed numerous letters, petitions, reports and underground publications (Samizdat) from believers of various denominations along with officially published books and periodicals.
Keston obtained materials documenting the religious and political climate in the German Democratic Republic between 1951 and 2004.
During the Potsdam Conference in 1945, Allies divided Nazi Germany into four occupation zones. In 1949, the Federal Republic of Germany, commonly called West Germany, was formed as the previously occupied area gained independence from the United States, Great Britain and France. In 1946, the Socialist Unity Party of Germany, also known as the SED, was formed under order from Joseph Stalin to govern the Soviet occupied zone. The German Democratic Republic (GDR), commonly called East Germany, was formed in 1949 from the part of Germany occupied by the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (USSR). Wilhelm Pieck became East Germany’s first president. The eastern border of the German Democratic Republic was the Oder-Neisse Line and the GDR surrounded West Berlin.
The United States posed the greatest threat to the German Democratic Republic. Therefore, the GDR issued anti-imperialist and anti-capitalist messages which were broadcast in various media and taught in schools. Communists also promoted state atheism, and in 1957, East Germany created the State Secretariat for Church Affairs to ensure adherence to atheism and to suppress religion in the arts, literature, and the media. Many political dissidents fled to West Germany while other citizens left because of religious policies. Thus, the GDR constructed the Berlin Wall in 1961 to fortify the border between East and West Berlin.
The German Democratic Republic became focused on creating a new identity that was separate from Prussia. Even while endeavoring to separate itself from its Prussian history, the GDR maintained close ties with both the Soviet Union and West Germany, despite strict immigration laws.
Ties between East and West Germany strengthened between 1971 and 1985 which is commonly referred to as the Honecker era after Eric Honecker, General Secretary of the Social Unity Party. During this period, the two countries did not refer to each other’s citizens as foreigners even though the Deutsche Grenzpolizei (German Border Police) and the Stazi (Ministry of State Security) actively monitored relationships between citizens of East and West Berlin.
The year 1989 brought rapid political change. In May, tensions rose in East Germany after the public learned of rigged government elections. Significant numbers of citizens again attempted to flee the country to Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Austria, and West Germany. Others stayed and protested the ruling party. Results of the German Democratic Republic’s first truly free parliamentary elections in March 1990 led to a governing coalition engineered by the Alliance for Germany which had won the most seats but not a majority in the Volkskammer (unicameral legislature). The Alliance had campaigned on a platform of rapid reunification. Mikhail Gorbachev’s Soviet programs of perestroika and glasnost also appeared to accelerate change in the region, and on October 3, 1990, East and West Germany were unified into the Federal Republic of Germany.
Scope and Content
GDR subject files consist of newspaper clippings, handwritten notes, magazine clippings, newsletters, church and secular publications, research papers, and reports on issues of religion and politics.
The materials cover a period from 1951 to 2007, with the bulk from 1977 to 1990. The most notable topics include, but are not limited to, the rise and fall of the Berlin Wall, Erich Honecker’s policies and legal trial, the fear and reign of the Stazi military police, and the unification of East and West Berlin.
Arrangement
The Keston Center received most of the GDR materials in files organized by specific categories and denominations. This original filing system has been preserved. The GDR materials received by the Keston Center in no particular order are arranged thematically and chronologically.
The German Democratic Republic Subject Files are now arranged into two series: I. General and II. Denominational materials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 6.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Honecker, Erich.
Subjects (Organizations)
Deutsche Evangelische Kirche -- History -- 20th Century.; Germany (East). Ministerium für Staatssicherheit.
Places
Germany (East) -- Armed Forces -- Military police.; Germany (East) -- Foreign Relations.; Germany (East) -- History.; Germany (East) -- Politics and government.; Germany (East) -- Religion.; Germany (East) -- Social life and customs.; Germany -- History -- Unification, 1990.
Subjects
Berlin Wall, Berlin, Germany, 1961-1989.; Church and state -- Germany (East); Church and State — Catholic Church.; Communism and Christianity -- Germany (East); Human rights -- Germany (East); Newsletters.; Protestant churches -- Germany (East)
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Manuscripts.
- General, 1951-2007; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  General GDR subject files contain materials on religious persecution, state religious policies, communist ideology, political leaders, religious publications, and international affairs.
  - History. General (1 of 5), 1961-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History. General (2 of 5), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History. General (3 of 5), 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History. General (4 of 5), 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History. General (5 of 5), 1989-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Individuals, 1982-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Nationalism. Minorities, 1978-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Government, 1975-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Elections (1 of 2), 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Elections (2 of 2), 1984-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - State. Government Nationalism. Individuals, 1981-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - State Policies, 1981-1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - State Administration, 1978-1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Military Affairs, 1978-1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Espionage, 1977-1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Emigration (1 of 2), 1973-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Emigration (2 of 2), 1984-1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Escapes (1 of 3), 1964-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Escapes (2 of 3), 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Escapes (3 of 3), 1984-1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Human Trafficking (Menchenhandel), 1975-1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Constitution. Law. Oppression, 1970-2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Law, 1968-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Law and Religion, 1956-1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Prisons. Labor Camps, 1964-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Oppressive Practices, 1966-1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Expulsion, 1968-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - International Relations. General, 1976-1990, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - International Relations with Africa and Middle East, 1972-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - International Relations with South America, Asia and Antarctica, 1977-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - International Relations with the EU and its countries, 1977-1988, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - International Relations with North America, 1973-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - International Relations with the USSR (1 of 2), 1956-1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - International Relations with the USSR (2 of 2), 1985-1990, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - International Relations with Great Britain, 1952-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - International Relations with China, 1981-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - International Relations with West Berlin (1 of 4), 1973-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - International Relations with West Berlin (2 of 4), 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - International Relations with West Berlin (3 of 4), 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - International Relations with West Berlin (4 of 4), 1988-1990, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - International Relations with West Berlin. Honecker, Erich. Neo-Nazi Survivors (1 of 3), 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - International Relations with West Berlin. Honecker, Erich. Neo-Nazi Survivors (2 of 3), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - International Relations with West Berlin. Honecker, Erich. Neo-Nazi Survivors (3 of 3), 1985-1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - International Relations with Poland, 1965-1990, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - International Relations with the Vatican, 1972-1989, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Peaceful Coexistence and Helsinki Agreement, 1977-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Western Reactions. Interventions. Pronouncements, 1977-1999, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Amnesty International, 1980-1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Peace Activities (1 of 2), 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Peace Activities (2 of 2), 1985-1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Protests. Dissidents. Illegal Activities, 1965-1990, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Demonstrations and Public Protests, 1977-1989, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Religion, 1983-2007, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - History of Religion. General, 1961-1990, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - History of Religion. Materials about Important Dates (Jan 30, 1933 and Jan 28, 1983), 1970-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Church and State. General, 1967-2005, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Church and State. Interdenominational, 1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lutheran Church and State, 1980-1999, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Protestant Church and State, 1975, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Catholic Church and State, 1970-1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Church and State. Effects of Emigration, 1977-1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bible, 1972-1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Evangelism. Conversions, 1975-1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Repressive Measures. Actions Taken, 1963-1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Repressive Measures. Individuals, 1982-1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Defection from Faith, 1978-1998, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Religion and Peace, 1977-1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Religion Abroad. General, 1977-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Religion Abroad. Africa, 1980-1986, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Religion Abroad. Chile, 1980-1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Religion Abroad. China, 1979-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Religion Abroad. Asia, 1980-1983, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Religion Abroad. Eastern Europe, 1980-1985, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Religion Abroad. Latin America, 1980-1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Religion Abroad. Poland, 1979-1984, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Religion Abroad. Vatican, 1979-1980, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Religion Abroad. Pope's Travels, 1979-1980, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Religion Abroad. Western Europe, 1976-1986, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Religion Abroad. USA, 1980-1985, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Visits Abroad, 1970-1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Visits From Abroad, 1965-1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Turned Church, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Family. Community. Holidays, 1978-2007, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Official Religious Publications, 1978-1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Revival, 1978-1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Religion and Science, 1983-1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Christian Democratic Union, 1968-1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Religion and Official Pronouncements, 1975-1987, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Theological Education, 1974-1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - World Council of Churches, 1969-1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Conference of European Churches, 1977-1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Taize, 1980-1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Religion and Media, 1977-1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Religion and Culture, 1979-1988, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Religion and Literature, 1979-1988, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bible (Interdenominational), 1951-1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Religious Tolerance, 1975-1989, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Youth, 1962-1989, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Atheism, 1970-1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Communist Ideology. Ethics. Philosophy. Morality ( 1 of 2), 1967-1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Communist Ideology. Ethics. Philosophy. Morality (2 of 2), 1985-1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Individual Communists. Honecker, Erich, 1971-1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Communism and Christianity, 1964-1987, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Communist Way of Life, 1963-1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Communist Schooling, 1975-1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Agriculture. Economy. Labor (1 of 2), 1963-1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture. Economy. Labor (2 of 2), 1983-1990, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Education. Science. Geography, 1965-1990, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Statistics, 1983-1988, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Health. Leisure. Sports. Tourism, 1965-1989, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Informational Services. TV. Radio. Press, 1987-1988, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Culture, 1972-1988, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Literature, 1965-1989, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Individuals, 1975-1988, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Arts. Architecture. Music, 1964-1989, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Women, 1979-2007, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Children and Youth, 1958-1999, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Society. Family. Everyday Life, 1872-1989, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Family, 1965-1990, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Everyday Life, 1963-1988, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Visual Material, 1986-1987, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - End of GDR. Anticommunism, 1989-1993, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - End of GDR. Berlin Wall, 1986-1997, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - End of GDR. Bombing of Dresden, 1990-1995, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - End of GDR. Ceremonies and Celebrations, 1980-1995, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - End of GDR. Children. Elderly. Families, 1980-1995, undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - End of GDR. Church Records, 1987-1993, undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - End of GDR. City Life, 1987-1999, undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - End of GDR. Communication with West Germany, 1981-1996, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - End of GDR. Ecumenical, 1987-1990, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - End of GDR. Foreign Affairs, 1981-1997, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - End of GDR. Kohl, Helmuth, 1990-1998, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - End of GDR. Medicine. Aid. Science, 1980-1994, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - End of GDR. Military. Police. Stasi, 1990-1998, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - End of GDR. Miscellaneous Arts, 1979-1997, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - End of GDR. Mistreatment. Arrests. Protests, 1981-1999, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - End of GDR. Neo-Nazi, 1988-1998, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - End of GDR. New Churches. Missionary Work, 1980-1993, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - End of GDR. Obituaries, 1990-1994, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - End of GDR. Papal Visits and Travel, 1981-1990, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - End of GDR. Political Parties, 1987-1997, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - End of GDR. Protestants, 1979-1991, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - End of GDR. Religion in Politics, 1980-1990, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Sports, 1990, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Subject Index. General Updates, 1979-1990, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - New Churches and Diplomats, 1967-1999 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Evangelical Church-State Relations, 1976-1989 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Wall Riots, 1978-1989 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Intra-German Relations, 1983-1998 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Scottish Churchmen, 1984-1985 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Neo-Nazi and Anti Fascism clippings, 1983-1985 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Hoenecker on Immigration/Emigration, 1985-1991 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - UBS World Report, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - reports: edp O, 1990-2000 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - UN Magazine, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Reports: IDL, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Reports: Idea Spektrum, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Reports: OKI, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Reports: BBC Transcript, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Reports: Soviet Analyst, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Reports: SWB, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Magazine: Time, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Reports: RDA, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Reports: Menschen Rechte, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Reports: Evangeliche Kirchen Presse, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Reports: European Baptist Press Service, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Reports: Rad Br, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Reports: Radio Free Europe, 1985-1986 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Reports: EPS, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Reports: LWI, 1986-1994 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - newspapers: Guardian, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Hoenecker, Gorbachev, and dissidents, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Politics and the Fall of the Berlin Wall, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Parties on Unification, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Public on the Wall, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Refugees, dissidents, and emigrant comments, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Kath Presse, 1990-2000 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Treaties and complaints, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Newspapers on dissatisfaction, 1992-2000 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Newspapers (1 of 2), 1985-1989 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Assorted Newspapers (2 of 2), 1990 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Photocopies, 1984-1991 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Periodicals, 1985-2001 (Box 28, Folder 3)
- Denominational, 1956-2004; 2
  Denominational GDR subject files contain categories similar to the general subject files with the focus on a particular denomination and individual prosecution cases of believers and clergy.
  - Baptists. General, 1970-2004, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Evangelical Church History (1 of 2), 1961-1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Evangelical Church History (2 of 2), 1980-1989, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Individual Evangelicals. Krusche, Albert-, 1975-1990, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Individual Evangelicals. Zeddies, Leich-, 1970-1989, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Evangelical Church Administration, 1969-1990, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Evangelical Church. The Patriarchate (1 of 2), 1970-1986 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Evangelical Church. The Patriarchate (2 of 2), 1987-1990, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Evangelical Church. Club "Bund", 1980-1990, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Evangelical Church. Theology (1 of 2), 1976-1990 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Evangelical Church. State. Law, 1976-1988, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Evangelical Church-State Relations (1 of 2), 1973-1983 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Evangelical Church-State Relations (2 of 2), 1984-2000, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Reopening (Opening of New) Evangelical Churches, 1975-1990, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Registration of Evangelical Churches, 1976-1990, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Evangelical Church. History. Church Supporters (1 of 2), June- Oct 1998 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Evangelical Church. History. Church Supporters (2 of 2), Nov 1998 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Evangelical Church. Oppressive Practices Relating to Religious Activity (1 of 2), 1965-1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Evangelical Church. Oppressive Practices Relating to Religious Activity (2 of 2), 1987-1993, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Evangelical Church Life, 1967-1987, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Evangelical Church. Services. Rituals. Liturgy, 1977-1989, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Evangelical Church. Modernization and Pilgrimage, 1974-1985, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Evangelical Church. Evangelism and Conversion, 1972-1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Evangelical Church. Parish Life, 1974-1989, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Evangelical Church. Defection from Faith, 1975-1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Evangelical Church. Secularization, 1977-1980, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Evangelical Church. Institutions, 1980-1988, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Evangelical Church. Geriatrics, 1980-1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Evangelical Church. Humanitarianism, 1978-1989, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Evangelical Church. Publications. Unions. Excommunications. Monasticism, 1976-1989, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Evangelical Church. Issues with Religious Life, 1980-1981, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Evangelical Church. Holy Week, 1977-1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Evangelical Church. Philanthropy, 1976-1990, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Evangelical Church. Clergy and Priesthood, 1974-1990, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Evangelical Church. International Relations and Western Reactions, 1968-1990, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Evangelical Church. Delegation Visits Abroad, 1966-1989, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Evangelical Church. Visits from Foreign Delegations, 1969-1990, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Evangelical Church. Religious Activities Approved by State, 1974-1988, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Evangelical Church. Theology. Philosophy. Ethics. Education, 1970-2000, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Evangelical Church. Theology (2 of 2), 1977-1985, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Evangelical Church. Religion. Ethics. Morals, 1971-1990, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Evangelical Church. Theological Education, 1977-1987, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Evangelical Church. Unity. Schisms. Doctrinal Differences, 1977-1989, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Evangelical Church. Statistics, 1965-1989, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)